Dr. Jimmye S. Hillman Papers 1933-2007
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Dr. Jimmye S. Hillman Papers 1933-2007
MS 569
Hillman, Jimmye S.
The Dr. Jimmye S. Hillman Papers contain writings, presentations, and speeches during his career as a professor of agricultural economics at the University of Arizona as well as a consulting economist for several committees and organizations.
20 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Dr. Jimmye S. Hillman (1923 – 2015), was a long-time professor at the University of Arizona - College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, an international economist, as well as a literary memoirist later in life.
Hillman was born in 1923 and grew up in Greene County, Mississippi on a subsistence farm. After graduating from Mississippi State University in 1942, Hillman served in the United States Army from 1942 to 1945, obtained a Master’s Degree from Texas A & M University in 1946, and a Ph.D. in agricultural economics from University of California, Berkeley, in 1950. Hillman joined the UA faculty in 1950, became head of the Department of Agricultural Economics in 1961, serving in that role until his retirement in 1990.
While at UA, Hillman trained generations of agricultural economists and took part in making the University a leader in the field. His research interests included agricultural and trade policies with some of his most significant work centered on the study of nontariff trade barriers. He authored two books, Nontariff Agricultural Trade Barriers (1978) and Technical Barriers to Agricultural Trade (1991), as well as numerous articles examining the globalization of food production and consumption, the proliferation of new food technologies, and the effects of agribusiness and technology on the environment, human health and social justice.
Additionally, he served as economist for the U.S. Agency for International Development in Brazil from 1957-1959, developed USAID Green Revolution projects in the Cape Verde Islands, and served as an advisor on agricultural policy to the government of Portugal when the nation was preparing to enter the European Union. In 1966-1967, Hillman was the Executive Director of the President's National Advisory Commission on Food and Fiber, appointed by President Lyndon Johnson, and in 1983-1984, chaired the agricultural study group assisting the President's Commission on United States-Japanese Relations, under President Ronald Reagan. He was also part of the Western States Manpower Advisory Committee established by the US Commission on Civil Rights. During 1972-1973, Hillman was a Visiting Research Fellow at Jesus College, University of Oxford as well as a visiting distinguished professor of economics at Lincoln University in Christchurch, New Zealand in 1995-1996 and received an honorary doctorate from the University of Ceará, Brazil in 1999.
In his retirement, Hillman focused his attention on writing in both creative non-fiction and the memoir. His account of his childhood during the Depression years, under the title of Hogs, Mules and Yellow Dogs, was published by University of Arizona Press in 2012.
Hillman passed away on June 4, 2015 due to complications of a stroke.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series
Series I: Correspondence, 1952-1999
Sub-Series I: General Correspondence, 1952-1964
Sub-Series II: Professional Correspondence, 1954-1999
Sub-Series III: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966-1999
Series II:Subject Files, 1933-1995
Sub-Series I: Water and Public Policy, 1933-1990
Sub-Series II: Food and Fiber Commission, 1965-1980
Sub-Series III: University of Arizona Administration Files, 1948-1993
Sub-Series IV: Other Consulting Work, 1954-1995
Series III:Scholarly Files, 1947-2007
Sub-Series I: Speeches and Publications, 1947-2007
Sub-Series II: Meetings and Trips, 1958-1998
Scope and Content Note
The Dr. Jimmye S. Hillman Papers span over the years, 1933–2007 (bulk 1960 – 1995), containing material on agricultural economics in the form of correspondence, writings, and presentations made throughout his career and lifetime. The papers highlight his involvement in the Commission on Food and Fiber and water resource policy.
Hillman, Jimmye S, 1923-.; University of Arizona.; UA College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; United States. Agency for International Development; Agriculture.; Agriculture -- Costs.; Agriculture -- Economics aspects -- United States -- Congresses.; Agriculture development projects.; Commerce --Congresses.; Economics.; Globalization.; Non-tariff trade barriers.; Produce trade -- Government policy.; Protectionism.; United States -- Commercial policy -- Congresses.; United States -- Commerce -- Congresses.; Tucson (Ariz.).
Container List
- Correspondence, 1952-1999; Series I
  The series is comprised of correspondence within general, professional (pertaining to both academic and consulting work), and miscellaneous subseries. In all three subseries, correspondence is listed chronological.
  - General Correspondence, 1952-1964; Subseries I
    - General Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, January 1954 - July 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, August 1954 – December 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, January 1955 – June 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, July 1955 – December 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence, January 1958 – June 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence, July 1958 – December 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - General Correspondence, January 1959 – March 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence, April 1959 – May 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - General Correspondence, June 1959 – July 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - General Correspondence, August 1959 – December 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - General Correspondence, January 1960 – March 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - General Correspondence, April 1960 – July 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - General Correspondence, August 1960 – September 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - General Correspondence, October 1960 – December 1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - General Correspondence, January 1961 – February 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - General Correspondence, March 1961 – May 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - General Correspondence, June 1961 – August 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - General Correspondence, September 1961 – October 1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - General Correspondence, November 1961 – December 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - General Correspondence, January 1962 – March 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, April 1962 – December 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Professional Correspondence, 1954-1999; Subseries II
    - Surplus Disposal – WFEA Correspondence/Papers, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Interstate Trade Barriers and Related Correspondence, 1954 - 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Lettuce Industry – Miscellaneous News Articles and Related Correspondence, 1954 - 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - WAEA Past Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1958 – 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Indian Study - Correspondence, 1959 – 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - England, 1960 – 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Brazil, 1960 – 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Sabbatical Leave Correspondence, 1962 – 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Foreign, 1962 – 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Agricultural Development Council Seminars/Related Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - United States House of Representatives – Correspondence and Testimony, November 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - IAAE Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1964 – 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - School Board Correspondence, 1965 – 1968 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Food and Fiber - General Correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Food and Fiber Commission Seminars - Programs and Correspondence, 1966 – 1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - WAEA Past Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1966 – 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Food and Fiber - Correspondence, January 1967 – March 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Food and Fiber - Correspondence, April 1967 – May 1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Food and Fiber - Correspondence, June 1967 – July 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Food and Fiber - Correspondence, August 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Food and Fiber - Correspondence, September 1967 – October 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Food and Fiber - Correspondence, November 1967 – December 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Speeches/Participation Correspondence Relating to Meetings and Seminars, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - United States Senate – Correspondence and Testimony, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - ILMA – Bogota, Columbia – Correspondence, February 1968 – July 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Speeches/Participation Correspondence Relating to Meetings and Seminars, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Food and Fiber - Correspondence, 1968 – 1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - ILMA – Bogota, Colombia – Correspondence, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - WAEA Correspondence, 1969 – 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Washington Correspondence, 1969 – 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - IAAE Meeting Correspondence and Notes on Russia - Minsk, Russia, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - President's Commission on International Trade and Investment Policy - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - AAEA Presidency - Correspondence, 1970 – 1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - First and Second Manpower Symposiums – Correspondence and Programs, 1970 – 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - General Foods Seminar - Related Correspondence, January 27, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Agricultural Policy for Developing Countries - Miscellaneous Correspondence about Arizona Workshop, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Carbondale Meeting - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Atlantic Council Study – Related Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Oxford Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Oxford Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Committee on Agricultural Production Efficiency (CAPE) – Correspondence, 1973 - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Task Force for Council for Agricultural Science and Technology (CAST) - Correspondence, 1973 – 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Arizona State House of Representatives – Correspondence, February 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - American University Symposium - Related Correspondence, October 1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Seminar in Storrs, Connecticut - Related Correspondence, December 2, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Trade Negotiations and World Food Problems Conference - Related Correspondence, December 5, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - FAO Reports and Correspondence about World Food Security, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Foreign, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Symposium on Energy, Environment, and Growth - Related Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - World Food Conference - Related Correspondence, 1974 - 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Various meetings and conferences related correspondence, 1974 – 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mexican-US Conference at University of Arizona – Correspondence, January 17, 1975 – January 18, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Great Plains Agricultural Policy Seminar - Related Correspondence, May 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Conference Document on Self-Sufficiency and Pertinent Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - FAO Consultation on World Food Security - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Senator's statement on Trade Negotiations - Related Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - US Food and Nutrition Policies and International Food Needs: An Analysis of Strategy Alternatives Study Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Foreign, 1975 – 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Quantitative Analyses of Grain Reserves Conference - Related Correspondence, April 1976 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Food and Trade Policies: A Commentary - Related Correspondence, November 1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Blue Sky Study Team - Related Correspondence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - SWIFT Trip - Related Correspondence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Symposium on International Trade and Agriculture - Correspondence, March 10, 1977 – March 11, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Review of Research Program - Department of Agricultural Economics, Auburn University Correspondence, December 1978 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Brazil Trip/International Communication Administration – Related Correspondence, May 1978 – June 1978 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - International Trade and Agriculture - Related Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - European Trip - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Nontariff Trade Barriers - Related Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis - Related Correspondence, 1979 – 1980 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Trips to Greece, Germany, and Austria - Related Correspondence, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Foreign, 1980 – 1986 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence – Dean Cardon, 1980 – 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - England, 1980 – 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Presidential Search Committee (1 of 2), August 1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Presidential Search Committee (2 of 2), August 1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Importance of Exports to US Agriculture - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - US-Japan Advisory Commission - Correspondence/Reports, January 1984 – May 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - US-Japan Advisory Commission - Correspondence/Reports, May 1984 – December 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - UK Agricultural Economics Society Meeting - Correspondence, March 22, 1985 – March 25, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - US Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry - Congressional Record and Related Correspondence, March 7, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Edmundo Flores Seminar - Correspondence, March 8, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Cape Verde Statistics Base Book and Related Correspondence, 1985 – 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - UK Agricultural Economics Society Conference - Correspondence, April 3, 1987 – April 6, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - National Public Policy Education Conference - Correspondence, September 14, 1987 – September 17, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - US - EC Conference on Agriculture – Correspondence, November 11, 1987 – November 14, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Foreign, 1987 – 1988 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - IAAE Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1987 – 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Technical Report for the Nile Agriculture and Food Industries Co. – Correspondence, 1987 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - American Graduate School of International Management Seminar - Correspondence, January 18, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Great Decisions 1988 Program - Correspondence, March 20, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Agricultural Trade and Protection in Japan - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Foreign, 1988 – 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - England, 1988 – 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Foreign, 1989 – 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - New Zealand Sabbatical – Related Correspondence, 1989 – 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - New Zealand Sabbatical – Speech Notes, Overheads, and Related Correspondence, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Technical Barriers to Agricultural Trade - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Australian Contacts, Meetings, and Related Correspondence, 1990 – 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - New Zealand Sabbatical – Related Correspondence, 1990 – 1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - IAAE XXI Correspondence - Tokyo, Japan, August 22, 1991 – August 29, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - New Zealand Sabbatical – Correspondence and Related Data, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Europe (1 of 2), 1991 – 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Europe (2 of 2), 1991 – 1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Foreign – Correspondence, 1991 – 1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Koffler, Henry – Correspondence, 1992 - 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - College of Agriculture - Correspondence, 1992 - 1995 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Rosen, Anthony - Correspondence, 1992 - 1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - State of Arizona - Correspondence, 1992 - 1995 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Washington, D.C. - Correspondence, 1992 - 1997 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Agricultural and Resource Economics Department – Correspondence, 1992 - 1998 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Campus, 1992 - 1998 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Hillman Endowment – Correspondence (1 of 2), 1992 - 1999 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Hillman Endowment – Correspondence (2 of 2), 1992 - 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bartley P. Cardon Endowed Chair, 1992 – 2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - New Zealand – Correspondence, 1993 – 1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Australia and New Zealand – Correspondence, 1993 – 1998 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Fulbright Application – Related Data and Correspondence, 1994 – 1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Seminars in Australia and Related Correspondence, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Henderson, Mary - Correspondence, 1997 – 1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Sabbatical Leave – Oxford, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966-1999; Subseries III
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966 – 1969 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1970 – 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972 – 1980 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - All Correspondence (Misc.), 1973 – 1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (A-M), 1990 – 1999 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (N-Z), 1990 – 1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Subject Files, 1933-1995; Series II
  The series is comprised of files that focus on specific subjects and projects that Dr. Hillman worked on over the years.
  - Water and Public Policy, 1933 - 1990; Subseries I
    Listed in chronological order, this subseries is comprised of papers, reports, and various correspondence related to water and public policy within the state of Arizona, along with a materials focused on the Central Arizona Project (CAP), Arizona’s single largest resource for renewable water supplies.
    - Salt River Project Annual Reports, 1933 – 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Agricultural Experiment Station - Published Materials, 1934 – 1964 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Testimony Before Senate Sub-Committee, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pumping for Irrigation Costs, 1951- 1952 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - City of Tucson, 1951 – 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Legal Issues of Ground and Surface Water, 1952 – 1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Salt River Project Crop and Stock Reports, 1955 – 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Land, Water, and Tax Values in Arizona, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Arizona Watershed Program, September 23, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Central Arizona Project Association, 1959 – 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - San Carlos Irrigation District, 1959 – 1964 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1960 – 1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Kelso, Maurice, Ph.D., 1960 – 1970 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Central Arizona Project Association Newsletter, 1961 – 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Arizona Water Statistics, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Rehnberg, Rex, September 10, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Pacific Southwest Water Plan, August 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Arizona Water Statistics, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - National Reclamation Association, 1963 – 1969 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - United States House of Representatives Testimony, November 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Yuma County – Irrigation, November 1964 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Arizona Water Statistics, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Fannin, Paul, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Maricopa County – Irrigation, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - McFarland, Ernest W., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Mohave County - Irrigation, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Pinal County – Irrigation, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1964 – 1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Western Interstate Water Conference, August 5, 1965 – August 6, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Arizona Water Statistics, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Colorado River Basin Project, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Pumping Water Costs in Central Arizona, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Udall, Morris K., 1965 – 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Central Arizona Project – Financing, December 14, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Myers, Dean Harold E., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1966 – 1967 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Goldwater, Barry, April 11, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Campbell, George W., Ph.D., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Young, Robert A., Ph. D., 1967 – 1969 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Central Arizona Project – Opponents, 1967 – 1975 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - University of Arizona – College of Agriculture, 1967 – 1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Data for Arizona Crop Farm Planning, June 1968 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Efficiency Analysis of Water Utilization in the Central Area of Arizona, December 1968 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Central Arizona Project – General, 1968 – 1972 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Martin, William, Ph.D., 1968 – 1982 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - The Need for Additional Water in the Arid Southwest: An Economist’s Dissent, February 1969 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - United States Department of the Interior, March 1969 – January 1972 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Role of Irrigation in the West’s Expanding Economy, May 26, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Colorado River Association Newsletter, 1969 – 1973 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1970 – 1971 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Johnson, Rich, March 30, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Ground-Water Conditions in the Harquahala Plains, Maricopa, and Yuma Counties, Arizona, April 1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Hillman, Jimmye, Ph.D. – Personal Notes, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1972 – 1973 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - University of Arizona – Department of Agricultural Economics, March 1974 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1974 – 1975 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Pima County – Irrigation, October 1976 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - University of Arizona – Interdisciplinary, 1979 – 1983 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Barr, George, 1981 – 1982 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1981 – 1985 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, 1986 – 1990 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Central Arizona Project – Press Clippings, undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Dawson, George, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - DeConcini, Evo, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Groundwater – General, undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Hayden, Carl, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Indian Tribes and Water, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Maps of Irrigation and Drainage, undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Modeling Production Response Relations for Irrigation Water: Review and Implications, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Salt River Project – General, undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Salt River Project – Miscellaneous, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Surface Water – General, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - United States Bureau of Reclamation, undated (Box 9, Folder 51)